

Gauray Kumar

Date of birth: 28/05/1997 | **Nationality:** Indian | **Gender:** Male | **Phone number:**

(+91) 8700759603 (Mobile) | **Email address:** gauravkumar28051997@gmail.com | **Website:**

https://gauravkumar-tech.github.io/portfolio/index.html | **Website:**

https://codewithgaurav.infinityfreeapp.com/?i=1

Address: RZF-338, GALI NO-22 SADH NAGAR, PALAM COLONY, 110045, DELHI,

India (Home)

ABOUT ME

IT Professional with 3.10 years of Experience in Software Development. Hands on experience with MicroServices, SpringBoot 5, Java JDK 7,8, Angular 9,14 OracleDB 11g, Spring, Flutter for mobile App development, Python and Artificial intelligence (a project based on A.I. with voice recognition and will work selenium for automation). Youtuber (CodeWithGaurav) Full stack Software Teacher.

PlayStore: CodeWithGaurav App

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/02/2020 - 31/01/2021 Noida, India

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (1 YEAR) ISPIDERS SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT TRAINING & PLACEMENT INSTITUTE

- 1. Backend Developer (Java JDK 8, Spring, Hibernate, Servlet, JDBC, Oops, Exception Handling, Core Java, Collections)
- 2. Frontend Development (Html 5, CSS, Javascript, ReactJs)
- 3. Database (MySQLServer) Client (SQLYog)

Responsibility

- 1. Job Portal Collection only (Java Collection Only) user can apply for Job on this. (solely Responsible)
- 2. Restaurant Bill Generation (Java Only) for restaurant Invoice generation. (solely Responsible)

Self Project with ReactJs + Java Spring boot + Mysql (**Conference Room**)

- 1. Will be usable for how many rooms are there with capacity.
- 2. Voice based conferencing.

01/02/2021 - 28/07/2022 Ghaziabad, India

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (1 YEAR, 4 MONTHS, 15 DAYS) JIL INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY LIMITED

- 1. Backend Developer (Java JDK 8, Spring, Hibernate, Collections, Spring MVC, Spring Boot)
- 2. Frontend Development (Html 5, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Angular 9)
- 3. Database (Oracle 11g) Client (Toad)

Responsibility

- 1. Handling a SOA University Project (Siksha 'O' Anusandhan (Deemed to be University), Build on JQuery and SpringMVC
- 2. Handling CampusLynx Project For JAYPEE INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, Build on Angular and Spring boot.

Responsible for working and creating modules as well as below.

- 1. Jasper Reports, Excels Reports, Pdfs (To extract Data in All these Formats acc. to requirement)
- 2. Microservice Modules (Financial Accounting, Fixed Assets, Biometrics, Admin, Inventory Procurement)
 Personal Project (Project named JARVIS) Python + Java + selenium + Automation + Voice Commands
 - 1. An A.I. named JARVIS which is able to interact with me by its own voice and can take my voice commands.
 - 2. Can search Google, Perform any function on computer i.e. opening file system, open or close any application.
 - 3. By using Java and selenium created a Jar file which will be responsible to connect to office system by VPN and Anydesk.
 - 4. JARVIS is responsible for handling this Jar by simply taking voice command from user.

01/08/2022 - 22/12/2023 Noida, India

SENIOR FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (1 YEAR, 5 MONTHS) INTELLYLABS TECHNOLOGIES

Responsibility

Website name - repairing company.com (From scratch)

- 1. Angular Skeleton Made for website Consists of Themes (black, white), Exception Handling, Multi-language Support
- 2. PayTm & Razor Pay Integration (payment Gateway integration with Website IsCheckout)
- 3. Discount/ Promo Code Features on Orders website
- 4. Automatic Mails Scheduling (Support email, Order Successful email, Incomplete email)
- 5. Microservices (Spring boot, Java)
- 6. Admin Portal
- 7. User Portal
- 8. Vendor Portal

Flutter (Android and IOS) - repairing comapany

- 1. PayTm Integration (All-In-One SDK)
- 2. Discount/ Promo Code Features on Orders
- 3. Wallet functionality for vendor's commission by which they can withdraw amount with PayTm & RazorPay directly.

28/11/2023 - CURRENT New Delhi, India

FULL STACK SOFTWARE TEACHER (YOUTUBER) 1 YEAR CODEWITHGAURAV - YOUTUBE

Responsibility:

Teaching Full Stack (Java Microservices & Angular) Concepts On YouTube, Concepts like:

- Monolithic vs Microservices
- Creating APIs (Java + SpringBoot)
- Creating Angular Project
- Building E-commerce website (Java microservice + Angular) with components like
 - a. Sending Google Emails (FTL + PDFs)
 - b. Documenting APIs (Swagger)
 - c. Authorization server and Gateway service implementation
 - d. Securing with Spring Security (JWT & Method level security)
 - e. Implementing Apache kafka, ELK Stack for microservice Logging
 - f. Google signin with Angular and User handling, Git Config Server with Github (External)
 - g. Data JPA Auditing & Dockerization & Creating images

Projects

- 1. Bulk emails sender using Gmail link Dockered Image Depolyed
- 2. Created Java Complier- Link Dockered Image Depolyed

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/04/2012 - 01/05/2013 Delhi, India

10TH SECONDARY SCHOOLING - 6.6CGPA Shiv vani model Sr. sec. school (CBSE)

Address Mahavir Enclave, Palam - Dabri Marg,, Dwarka, New Delhi, Delhi , 110045, Delhi, India | Website http://www.shivvani.in/

01/05/2013 - 01/05/2015 Delhi, India

10+2 (12TH) HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOLING - 65.8% Shiv vani model Sr. sec. school (CBSE)

Address Mahavir Enclave, Palam - Dabri Marg, , Dwarka, New Delhi, Delhi , 110045, Delhi, India | Website http://www.shivvani.in/

15/08/2016 - 15/08/2020 Delhi, India

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY(MECHANICAL AND AUTOMATION ENGINEERING) - 6.84CGPA (4 YEARS) Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University

Address GGSIPU, Golf Course Rd, Sector 16 C, Dwarka,, 110078, Delhi, India | Website http://ipu.ac.in/

DIGITAL SKILLS

FrameWorks Spring Boot AngularJS Micro Services RestAPI | Mobile app Development (Flutter) | Microsoft Office | Git | Java | SQL | Object-Oriented Programming | CSS | Github | MySQL | HTML | JavaScript | Linux | Web Development | JSON | RESTful api | Python Language - Basic knowledge | Devops: Docker, Jenkins